let X be a positive real number and
assume that X is greater than or equal
to 1x consider a right triangle with one
leg of length 2 and the other leg of
length x -
1X as this is a right triangle we can
use the Pythagorean theorem to find the
length of the hypotenuse in terms of the
legs in this case we see that the
hypotenuse length is the < TK of 2^2
plus the quantity x - 1x^2 and this
simplifies to x + 1 overx but in any
right triangle the hypotenuse is longer
than the leg lengths and so in this
situation we see that the quantity x +
1X is greater than or equal to 2 this
inequality is true for any positive real
number X because we can interchange X
and 1 /x can you see from the diagram
when equality holds